<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Highlights feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Riley J. Shaw is an artist, engineer, and educator. Focused on accessibility, mentorship, and community, Riley questions who “digital literacy” serves.]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 07:11:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Feature: add a dark theme]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Dark themes are something I’ve sought since my early days on a computer. I remember finding a way to apply a black background to Microsoft Word 2003, then being horrified when I accidentally printed the document. In uni I scripted my desktop to boot into <a href="https://justgetflux.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">f.lux</a>’s darkroom mode. One of my only lasting contributions to <a href="/blog/the-pool-on-the-roof-must-have-a-leak">Signal</a> was loudly advocating for dark mode on iOS and Desktop, not just Android. I even <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/dark-theme-everywhere/nibjplbnmmklkfnkpecgbffkifmdbjed" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">made a browser extension in 2015</a> to apply a dark theme to the entire Internet.</p>
<p>It’s not the most pressing or exciting work, but I decided my site should have a dark theme of its own. I took a lot of inspiration from my former Khan Academy teammate <a href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/dark-mode/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Josh W. Comeau’s dark mode post</a>, with a few differences.</p>
<p>UI-wise, I decided to go a different route than a binary toggle between dark and light. There were three motivations behind this. From most to least important:</p>
<ul>
<li>I wanted to include a “system” option. Theming is still a fresh concept for most web users, so I think it’s worthwhile to expose a way to control theme, motion, brightness etc from within the webpage. But <a href="https://kilianvalkhof.com/2020/design/your-dark-mode-toggle-is-broken" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">there should <em>always</em> be a simple way to revert back to your system’s display preferences</a>.</li>
<li>I may add more options later (greyscale? low-res? melty??) and this leaves my options open and unlimited.</li>
<li>I liked the animated eyeball idea.</li>
</ul>
<p>Speaking of the animated eyeball… I’m happy with how it turned out! It was quite a deep dive, since I didn’t want to include a heavy animation library like <a href="https://www.react-spring.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">react-spring</a> (&gt;25kb) or <a href="https://www.framer.com/motion/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Framer Motion</a> (&gt;90kb). <strong>Thankfully, the coolest thing I learned while working on this feature is that <a href="https://css-tricks.com/guide-svg-animations-smil/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SVG has a declarative animation specification called SMIL</a>!</strong> It didn’t take long to pick up, and it’s very easy to work with. I’m really happy to add it to my toolkit.</p>
<p>Animations were the <em>coolest</em> deep dive, but they weren’t the deepest. Back when I started building this website, I split the header into Cyan, Magenta, and Yellow (CMY) channels. They <a href="/blog/your-art-teacher-lied">combined subtractively</a> to make a black-ish color, which I used across the site for text. I removed that feature in late 2019, but recently added it back.</p>
<p>With a single theme, that’s three combinations, for a total of 7 colors. With two themes… the combinations explode a bit.</p>
<p>I use <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/mix-blend-mode" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">mix-blend-modes</a> to combine colors, of which there are limited options. For my initial color palettes, I wanted to pick three pretty primary colors (light: CMY, dark: RGB) that would blend into three pretty secondary colors (light: RGB, dark: CMY), and all blend together into something with enough contrast from the background to use as body text. Tall order! <a href="https://github.com/rileyjshaw/palette-test-tool" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">So I built a tool for that</a>, and spent a few idle hours tweaking settings until I was happy.</p>
<p>And the initial palettes are… pretty good? I wish I was more thrilled with the result, but there are so many conflicting requirements that it’s impossible to get a result as good as if I’d hand-picked the colors independently. I’ve done an initial a11y pass of the colors, and there are some areas of the site where I want to improve the contrast. So I’ll probably end up with a palette split between the “true” colors, and their slightly modified, more attractive cousins.</p>
<p>I also needed to add a global settings provider in this commit. Now that I’ve done the work for that, look forward to more settings (reduce motion, contrast preference, block embeds… cheat codes??) coming soon!</p>
<p>I made a few minor changes while working on this commit:</p>
<ul>
<li>Update a bunch of the site doodles to fit either theme.</li>
<li>Share theme colors between CSS-land and JS-land. No more mismatches!</li>
<li>Keep the <code>&lt;Layout&gt;</code> component mounted between pages. Transitions and performance will be just <em>sliiightly</em> smoother.</li>
<li>Clarify the color variables a bit; <code>--cb</code> is now <code>--color-blue</code>. - Add theme-dynamic color variables. For instance, <code>--color-p1</code> (“primary one”) maps to <code>--color-red</code> in dark mode and <code>--color-cyan</code> in light mode.</li>
<li>Update some non-standard colors (eg. scaling faders demo) to fit the new palettes.</li>
<li>Super simplify state-handling in the site nav (fixes a persistent console error).</li>
<li>Standardize the handling of <code>localStorage</code> and <code>sessionStorage</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hope you enjoy!</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/1c9ceef36f4fef69fd3a20b65414de774f3bf3e1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_1C9CEEF36F4FEF69FD3A20B65414DE774F3BF3E1</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feature: add an embed blocker for external media 🔐]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Makes page loads snappier, and lets folks opt into Google’s tracking empire</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/0065325b42759a67cc72cbad73c5f1d97bdf2857</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_0065325B42759A67CC72CBAD73C5F1D97BDF2857</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Release: remove the “beta” banner!!! 🎊]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Almost one year ago, I <a href="http://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/acfbf166206e1fcea9f03b6919715eba01e4b2f9" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">quietly launched the new version of my site to rileyjshaw.com</a>. It was the last day of the decade, and it felt momentous. But since there were still some glaring bugs and omissions, I decided to hedge the release behind a “THIS SITE IS IN BETA” banner.</p>
<p>It’s the end of the year again. Though there are <em>still</em> design problems and omissions, the site is much further along than it was on initial release. Some highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/lab">/lab</a> no-longer crashes Webkit based browsers (lol)</li>
<li>I added <em>bunch</em> of new scrapers. Most recently: SoundCloud, Vimeo, and YouTube.</li>
<li>The design is still uh… getting there… but it’s at least simpler and more consistent now.</li>
<li>I test-drove the blog and added some new features (like MDX!)</li>
<li>I put a ton of meat on last year’s skelly bones. From <a href="/about">/about</a> to <a href="/lab">/lab</a> to adding about 3x more quotes, this site is more substantial and chaotic than ever before.</li>
</ul>
<p>There have been about 130 commits between the beta release and this one. It’s not much for a whole year, but fixing up my personal website felt pretty small and self-indulgent vs. everything else I was focusing on. And 130 is still plenty of work to call this beta version un-betafied!</p>
<p>I was initially going to remove the banner on New Year’s Eve, but I’d rather do it early and spend the rest of the year offline. That feels like the biggest improvement in this whole feature list.</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/5edf7cab0d844a346f49222f92a84005b0f01433</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_5EDF7CAB0D844A346F49222F92A84005B0F01433</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feature: add a video scraper]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I figure now that I’m scraping SoundCloud, I’d better start scraping YouTube and Vimeo too. Since I occasionally cross-post videos (eg. a demo / instructional video for Patchstorage), I need to figure out how to reduce the clutter caused by duplicate entries. I’ll solve that problem once I see where duplicates tend to crop up.</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/4d115d10aa58b7606b7ef4ad1c750e4bf4c56fc7</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_4D115D10AA58B7606B7EF4AD1C750E4BF4C56FC7</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feature: add a SoundCloud song scraper]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>For now it’s mostly experiments and technical demos, but as I get braver I might start posting more music :)</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/76a558dfd30b60806e4d7cd42ab37ef0737c3f31</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_76A558DFD30B60806E4D7CD42AB37EF0737C3F31</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feature: add lazy loading to the lab]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This small, very important change has been in my working directory since January. What a year…</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw.github.io/0cdfad1d54b6ce4317efc6775f67c9c12827bcd0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_0CDFAD1D54B6CE4317EFC6775F67C9C12827BCD0</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scaling faders (audio demo)]]></title><link>https://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/ZEOqdPM</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SCALING_FADERS_(AUDIO_DEMO)</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[guyz]]></title><link>https://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/jObpqem</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_GUYZ</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deletion Day]]></title><link>https://deletionday.com</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_DELETION_DAY</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[PO-33 loader]]></title><link>https://glitch.com/edit/#!/po-33?path=README.md</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_PO_33_LOADER</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plop]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/plop</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_PLOP</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Add pagination to the blog!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This is an exciting commit for the new site. It collects blog posts from multiple sources (for now: <a href="http://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">http://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com</a>, <a href="https://sfpc.rileyjshaw.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://sfpc.rileyjshaw.com</a>, and <a href="/blog">https://rileyjshaw.com/blog</a>), orders them by date, and paginates them into a nice on-site list.</p>
<p>In the past, my blog has always seemed stale and outdated. By allowing it to gobble content from across the web, I can point it to whatever platform I'm currently publishing on!</p>
<p>This commit is going to show up as a post on my blog, which feels rather meta.</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw-new/13f32fb1219d29a61032646be13dcfe602a595f5</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_13F32FB1219D29A61032646BE13DCFE602A595F5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bootstrap an independent data scraper]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Project scraper</h1>
<p>The projects on my site are automatically scraped and formatted at publish time using the scripts in this directory. Read more about my reasoning below, or skip to the <a href="#structure">directory structure</a>.</p>
<h2>Why?</h2>
<p>Gatsby's source and transformer plugins are powerful, and I used them in the initial development of this site. I eventually decided that separating my collection process would be good for flexibility, control, and offline work.</p>
<h3>Flexibility</h3>
<p>GraphQL's filters and transforms are powerful, and Gatsby's APIs add more options for how data is fetched, cached, and transformed. However, complicated or non-standard data transforms and sanitization are much easier outside of Gatsby's ecosystem. For instance, the API starts to feel clunky for one-off treatment of specific content nodes,</p>
<h3>Control</h3>
<p>I've had a good experience with Gatsby but I may decide to migrate my site to another platform or format someday. Keeping my data entirely separate from the from the site's framework makes migrating my data as easy as copy/pasting this directory. It's just a few JS files!</p>
<h3>Offline</h3>
<p>Gatsby stores requests made through its source plugins in the <code>.cache</code> directory by default. The <code>.cache</code> directory is deleted after:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>gatsby clean</code> is called.</li>
<li><code>package.json</code> changes, for example a dependency is updated or added.</li>
<li><code>gatsby-config.js</code> changes, for example a plugin is added or modified.</li>
<li><code>gatsby-node.js</code> changes, for example if a new Node API is invoked.</li>
<li>…etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>I found I was frequently triggering <code>.cache</code> wipes during development. At best this meant I was pinging APIs and atom feeds more than necessary. At worst, it made working offline with project data impossible.</p>
<h2>Directory structure</h2>
<p>Here's how the scraper is organized for now:</p>
<pre><code>scrape-projects.js
	The megafile to replace Gatsby's source plugins. This pulls project data
	from all online sources and saves them into `_generated/`.

_generated/
	Files generated by the `scrape-projects.js` above. DO NOT EDIT THESE FILES
	MANUALLY! They will be overwritten.

	scraped-projects-raw.json
		Not quite the raw response, but pretty close. This file
		contains all the data that I may decide to use someday, but
		haven't yet. Organized by `type` in a nested object.

    scraped-projects-formatted.json
		Standardized into a smaller format that can be smashed together with
		`curation/` data. Flattened into an array with `type` annotations on
		each node, as well as unique, unchanging project IDs (`UID`).

curation/
	This is where all custom curation and processing go, eg. tagging content.
	Projects are modified based on their generated UID.

	tweaks.js
		Mainly for one-off changes eg. fixing formatting errors from immutable
		online sources. This file can also be used to apply changes on groups
		of files.

	tags.js
		TODO: figure out where `tags`, `lastTagged`, and `coolness` data are
		going to live.

sources/
	Offline data files and collections to compliment the online data cached in
	`_generated/`.

	standalone-projects.json
		TODO: Move these over from the `src/data` directory.

tools/
	Custom tools to help classify, organize, or edit project nodes without
	opening a text editor. Custom tools are only built for data that is too
	difficult to keep updated or standardized manually.
	TODO: Hook these up to a Node server so they edit the JSON files directly.

	tagger.html
		Finds untagged or incorrectly tagged projects, as well as projects
		that were last tagged before a new tag type was added. Provides an
		interface to preview and re-tag each project.

	cool-sort.html
		TODO: sort or insert nodes based on their "coolness".

test/
	Quick test files to ensure data is downloaded without any dropped nodes,
	UIDs are unique, etc.
</code></pre>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw-new/2488bcd5e5610f692773e7815fabdb247ece55f5</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_2488BCD5E5610F692773E7815FABDB247ECE55F5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firehose: proof of concept]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm experimenting with auto-generating nodes for <a href="/lab">https://rileyjshaw.com/lab</a> from a variety of data sources. This project may eventually replace <a href="/">https://rileyjshaw.com</a>.</p>
<p>This is the initial commit, completed quickly as a proof of concept. There's nothing much to show, but I want to deploy ASAP so I can test the full pipeline.</p>
<p>So far, everything has worked! Data from a variety of sources is already appearing on my local server. To reproduce:</p>
<ul>
<li>Run <code>gatsby develop</code>.</li>
<li>Open <a href="http://localhost:8000/page-2" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">http://localhost:8000/page-2</a> in a browser.</li>
</ul>
<p>So far, I'm surfacing data from:</p>
<ul>
<li>A hand-curated JSON list of projects I use for <a href="/lab">https://rileyjshaw.com/lab</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://dwitter.net" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dwitter</a>'s API.</li>
<li><a href="https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">My commit--blog</a>'s Atom feed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Setting this up was <em>EASY</em>, which makes me excited for the future of this experiment :)</p>]]></description><link>https://rileyjshaw.commit--blog.com/rileyjshaw/rileyjshaw-new/f117f4faa75dca5fa109bac066adb3b3ee5c6cf7</link><guid isPermaLink="false">COMMIT_F117F4FAA75DCA5FA109BAC066ADB3B3EE5C6CF7</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Servo]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/Servo/tree/min-max-improvements</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SERVO</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[typing lazy (desktop only)]]></title><link>https://typing-lazy.glitch.me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TYPING_LAZY_(DESKTOP_ONLY)</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Huertbeat]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/huertbeat</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_HUERTBEAT</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[canvas]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/canvas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CANVAS</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[write]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/write</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_WRITE</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crypto Christmas]]></title><link>https://crypto.christmas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CRYPTO_CHRISTMAS</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RileyJShaw.???]]></title><link>https://gist.github.com/rileyjshaw/216af3d73b16e35d462ea5a29da4bcd4</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_RILEYJSHAW.???</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cyber pilot (with controls)]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/YGQVqK?editors=1000</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CYBER_PILOT_(WITH_CONTROLS)</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[w h a t]]></title><link>http://www.lexaloffle.com/bbs/?tid=27571</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_W_H_A_T</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virtuoso]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/virtuoso</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_VIRTUOSO</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Keyboard keyboard]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/keyboard-keyboard</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_KEYBOARD_KEYBOARD</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Typing for two]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/typing-for-two</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TYPING_FOR_TWO</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Single line tiling]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/collection/nYWPBp/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SINGLE_LINE_TILING</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Literate theme]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/literate-theme</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_LITERATE_THEME</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Circling circles]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/xVQBLG/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CIRCLING_CIRCLES</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jittery visualizer v2]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/oxaxqX/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_JITTERY_VISUALIZER_V2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Typelab]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/eZrzbK/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TYPELAB</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Astronomie & Astrophysique]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/PNPVmK/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_ASTRONOMIE_&amp;_ASTROPHYSIQUE</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mechanical waves]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/collection/XWQERV/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_MECHANICAL_WAVES</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[whoami.py]]></title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/eliawry/poetics/master/whoami.py</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_WHOAMI.PY</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dark Theme Everywhere]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/dark-theme-everywhere</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_DARK_THEME_EVERYWHERE</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[XOXO Bingo]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/xoxo-bingo</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_XOXO_BINGO</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Touchtone math facts]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/touchtone-math-facts</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TOUCHTONE_MATH_FACTS</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shepard-Risset Glissando]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/OPwROr?editors=001</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SHEPARD_RISSET_GLISSANDO</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Challenger]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/challenger</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CHALLENGER</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[28 Hour Day]]></title><link>https://apps.getpebble.com/en_US/application/54cadfd211e375bdc5000048</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_28_HOUR_DAY</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hackers.cool]]></title><link>http://hackers.cool/~rileyjshaw/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_HACKERS.COOL</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fingerprint]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/tappy-fingerprint</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_FINGERPRINT</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tappy]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/tappy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TAPPY</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Folding tutorial concept]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/raNLdL/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_FOLDING_TUTORIAL_CONCEPT</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tic Attack Toe]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/tic-attack-toe</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TIC_ATTACK_TOE</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reaction]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/visited-vectors/reaction</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_REACTION</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tappy game]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/tappy-game</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TAPPY_GAME</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Film-grain effect in 117B of JavaScript]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/enfkc</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_FILM_GRAIN_EFFECT_IN_117B_OF_JAVASCRIPT</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Super slinky]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/pIFly/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SUPER_SLINKY</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pairjam]]></title><link>https://github.com/neerajwahi/pairjam</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_PAIRJAM</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Placid tab]]></title><link>https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/placid-tab/mjcblgoejhkkkhgeadejhkpldglnfmcj</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_PLACID_TAB</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linescapes]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/linescapes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_LINESCAPES</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Graphing depth]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/collection/amDJo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_GRAPHING_DEPTH</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sweep]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/sweep</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SWEEP</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Own this website]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/own-this-website</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_OWN_THIS_WEBSITE</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tiny boxes]]></title><link>https://github.com/rileyjshaw/boxes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TINY_BOXES</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[terra]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/terra</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_TERRA</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CSS slope illusion in <140 characters]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/vzwsu/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_CSS_SLOPE_ILLUSION_IN_&lt;140_CHARACTERS</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Planets]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/yenLw</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_PLANETS</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2p Snake]]></title><link>https://rileyjshaw.com/2p-snake</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_2P_SNAKE</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sass animation grid]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/full/zGnlq</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_SASS_ANIMATION_GRID</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Long-shadow input series]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/collection/EJveu</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_LONG_SHADOW_INPUT_SERIES</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Worst practices]]></title><link>http://codepen.io/rileyjshaw/pen/cKiDn?editors=0010</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_WORST_PRACTICES</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zenwall]]></title><link>http://youtu.be/zQ5tKU3z1fc</link><guid isPermaLink="false">PROJECT_ZENWALL</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>